（ナルト）ハァ　ハァ…。
（オビト）なぜ起き上がる？
Why do you get up?!
こんな世界のために
もう戦う意味はないはずだ。
There is no reason to keep on
fighting for a world like this.
この世界も　数分で終わる。
In a few minutes,
this world will be gone anyway.
そうまでして　なぜ戦う？
Why do you still fight?
自分の忍道だからだ。
Because it's my Ninja Way.
まっすぐ自分の言葉は曲げねえ。
I never go back on my word.
それが　俺の忍道だからだ。
That's my Ninja Way.
眠れと言ったはずだ。
I thought I told you to go to sleep!
（サスケ）次で決着をつけるぞ　ナルト。
Let's settle this with
our next move, Naruto!
おう！
Right!
眠るのは明日。
We'll sleep tomorrow,
dreaming our own dreams!
夢は　自分で見る！
Ready, set, go, we step over the goal line
isse nou se de fumikomu gourain
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
We look back as we pass the line, and it's already gone
issen koete furikaeruto mou nai
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
Fiercely, fiercely we move on
udatte udatte udatteku
Drenched in glistening sweat
kirameku ase ga koboreru no sa
There probably were a lot of things we didn't remember
oboetenai koto mo takusan atta darou
Everyone was just a silhouette
daremo kare mo shiruetto
Let's become adults,
daiji ni shitai mono motte otona ni naru nda
holding on to things we want to cherish
And let's keep on protecting them at all times
donna toki mo hanasazu ni mamori tsudzukeyou
Then someday...
soshitara itsu no hi ni ka
We'll be able to laugh at it all
nanimo kamo o waraerusa
Like the light and nimble dancing
hirari to hirari to matteru
Of leaves taking flight
konoha ga tonde yuku
A Heart Filled with Comrades
《重吾：須佐能乎が…》
The Susano'o is...
（柱間）あれは！
That's...
かつてのマダラがやったのも
こんな感じか。
I believe this is what
Madara did once before.
（カカシ）これは　ナルトとサスケ？
This is... Naruto and Sasuke?
今更　何をしようと変わらんぞ。
Nothing you try now
will change anything.
上を見ろ。
Look above you...
この天井の穴から何が見える？
What can you see through
that hole at the top?
《オビトの見るもの
声が入ってくる…。
I can see what Obito sees...
and hear his voice.
共鳴か…》
It's resonating.
月だ　月夜の夢の世界へ
向かうときは近づいている。
The moon.
The time to enter
the moonlit dream world nears.
大きく開いた地獄の穴を
月の夢が埋めてくれる。
The gaping hole of hell
that has opened will be filled
by the moon's dreams...
やっと　そのときが来たのだ。
That time is finally here!
((見てみろ！　俺の心には
何もありゃしない。
Look!
There's nothing in my heart!
今は　もう痛みさえ感じやしない。
I don't even feel pain anymore.
現実は残酷だ。　この穴が
広がるだけでしかない。
Reality is cruel...
This hole will only keep growing larger.
(こんな世界にいて
どうやってこの穴を埋める？))
How will you fill this hole
by staying in this world?
（オビト）この剣は六道仙人の神剣
ぬのぼこの剣だ。
This sword is the divine blade
of the Sage of the Six Paths...
the Nunoboko.
もう　キサマらは俺には勝てん。
You can no longer defeat me.
想いの強さが剣に宿る　心の剣だ。
Strong emotions dwell within the blade.
It's a sword of the soul.
仙人は　この剣で
この世界を創造した。
The Sage created the world
with this blade.
（キバ）おい　みんな　今の…。
（シノ）ああ。
Hey... did you feel that... just now?
Yeah...
（リー）テンテン　これって。
（テンテン）うん　行くわよ　リー！
Tenten, isn't this...?
Yeah. Let's go, Lee!
（シカマル）アイツが呼んでる。
He's calling us.
（オビト）俺の想いは　キサマらに勝る。
My desire will vanquish you all.
どんなに　あがこうとも
もう意味はない。
No matter how much you resist,
it's useless.
仙人の力が　キサマらを止める。
The power of the Sage will stop you.
サスケ　俺たちは一撃に集中する。
Sasuke...
Let's focus everything on
a single blow.
ほんの小さなスキしか
できねえだろう。
I think we're only gonna have
a tiny window to strike.
見逃すなよ。
フン！
Don't miss it.
そして俺が　この剣で
この世界を消す！
And I will use this sword
to obliterate this world!
《オビト…　最初は　バカにしていても→
Obito...
Even if it's someone
they used to make fun of...
人は人一倍　頑張るヤツを見ると→
when people see someone
trying twice as hard as others,
おのずと手を差し伸べたくなる。
they instinctively start wanting
to lend a hand.
心の穴は　互いに埋め合うことを→
That's because...
people eventually learn
that they only have each other
人は　いずれ
知ることになるからだよ》
to fill the holes in their hearts.
《螺旋丸は　みんなに託す！
I'm giving a Rasengan
to each of you!
うまく　ヤツの盾を
ぶっ壊してくれってばよ！》
Use it to blast through his shield!
《これね！》
This, right?
《僕が　うまくできるかな？》
Can I really do this?
《大丈夫！》
You can!
《そして　その仲間で満ちた
心を持つ者は…》
And he who possesses
a heart filled with comrades...
《強い…》
is truly powerful!
《サクラ：行って　みんな！》
Go get him, everyone!
（２人）ハァーッ！
《オビト：なぜ俺は　こんなイメージを…》
Why am I...
seeing such images...?
（九喇嘛）思ったとおりだ。
Just like we thought!
お前がもらった
尾獣どものチャクラに呼応して→
The chakra you received
from the Tailed Beasts earlier
reacted to the Tailed Beast Chakra
inside him and
一撃で　ヤツから
尾獣チャクラを引っ張り出せたぞ。
you were able to pull it all out
in one shot!
だな。
Yeah!
This wouldn't have worked
《あのとき
尾獣どもに気に入られ→
if the Tailed Beasts hadn't taken a liking
to you back then
チャクラをもらってなきゃ
できなかった芸当だ》
and shared their chakra with you.
((孫：俺は　俺の止め方を
教えたまでだ。
I only told you how to stop me.
助け方までは教えてねえよ。
I never told you how to save me.
You should have told me that
from the beginning!
初めっから　そっち
教えてくれってばよ。
なんで　そんな
素直じゃねえんだよ。
Why aren't Tailed Beasts
more straightforward?!
みんな　尾獣ってのは。　はぁ…。
で　どうすんの？
So what are you gonna do?
Before I tell you,
I have something to pass on to you.
その前に
お前に渡してぇもんがある。
何？
手　出せ。
What?
Hold out your hand...
うん？　なんか　くれんのか？
Huh? You're giving me something?
いいもんだ。
そのうち役に立つぜ。
It's something good.
It will come in handy one of these days.
早くしろ。
Hurry up!
（ウタカタ）
俺たちは　四尾の訴えで集い→
We assembled here
on Four Tails' summons...
And hung around after promising to tell
and give you something.
お前に聞かせ
渡すものを約束して　ここにいる。
そっか。　アイツ　そんなこと…。
Oh, he said something like that?
ヘヘッ！　とにかく　みんな集まって→
I'm glad that you're all gathered together
and getting along!
仲よさそうで　よかったってばよ。
（ハン）そうなったのは　ここより
四尾と老紫がいなくなった→
That only happened after Four Tails
and Roshi left here.
あとのことだで　ナルト。
お前のおかげだ。
It's all thanks to you, Naruto.
（又旅）ナルト君　前にきて手を。
Naruto, step forward
and extend your hand...
四尾…　いや
孫悟空との約束を果たします。
We shall now fulfill
our promise to Four Tails...
rather Son Goku.
私の名は　又旅。
My name is Matatabi.
（ユギト）二位ユギト。
Yugito Ni'i...
（磯撫）僕の名は　磯撫。
一度　会ってるよね。
My name is Isobu.
We've met before, huh!
（やぐら）
俺は　元四代目水影　やぐらだ。
I'm Yagura,
the former Fourth Mizukage.
（穆王）私は穆王。
I am Kokuo.
ハンだ。
I'm Han.
（犀犬）俺やよ　犀犬ってんだ。
Me, I be called Saiken.
改めて　ウタカタだ。
You already know me, I'm Utakata.
（重明）ラッキーセブン　重明だ。
I'm Lucky Seven Chomei.
(（フウ）フウっす！))
I'm Fu!
《ナルト　お前ってヤツは　本当によ！》
Naruto...
You really are something special...
今だ！
Now!
You know what to do next, right, Naruto?
ここからは　わかってるな　ナルト！
例の綱引きだ！
It's a tug-of-war!
そのまま尾獣どものチャクラを
引き抜く！
Just pull the Tailed Beasts' chakra
right out of him!
おう！
Yeah!
Damn!
チッ！　持ってなかった
一尾と八尾に関しちゃダメか！
I guess it won't work with One Tail
and Eight Tails
because we never got their chakra.
（我愛羅）もともとは
俺と繋がっていた一尾だ。
One Tail used to be linked to me.
I'll get him.
俺がやる！
我愛羅！
Gaara!
《こっちへ来い　守鶴》
Come here, Shukaku!
（キラービー）やっと弱点を暴露！
八っつぁんのチャクラは俺に任せろ！
We finally found a weakness,
that's the key!
You can leave Eight-o's chakra to me!
ビーのおっちゃん！
Octopops!
（牛鬼）やるぜ　ビー！　負けんなよ！
Let's do this, Bee! Don't lose!
ヘッ！
引き抜け！
そうすりゃヤツの力は→
Extract them!
Then the only power he'll have left
is the Ten Tails' shell!
十尾の抜け殻だけになる！
大樹の花も開きはせん！
And the Divine Tree's bud
will not bloom!
クッ！
（ヒルゼン）止まった…。
They've stopped...
Which means...
《これは　ヤツが　大樹を
コントロールできていないということ。
he's lost control of the Divine Tree!
つまり…》
In other words...
《シカマル：みんな。
Everyone...
Remember when I said that
even a small power can be helpful
小さな力でも
要は使いようだって言ったな。
depending on how it's used?
Now is the time!
今がそのときだ。
That power will change
the course of this world...
その力が世界を左右する。
聞いてくれ》
Listen closely.
ヤツとチャクラがつながっているからだ。
It's because your chakra
is connected to his!
His feelings will flow into you,
but don't let them distract you!
ヤツの心が入ってくるが
惑わされるな。
六道仙人と等しい
十尾人柱力の力を　なめるな！
Don't underestimate
the power of the Ten Tails' Jinchuriki.
I'm equivalent to
the Sage of the Six Paths!
フンッ！
いいから引け　ナルト！
Just keep pulling, Naruto.
ナルト　手を貸せっつったのはお前だ。
Naruto! You're the one
who asked us to lend a hand!
最後まで手は出させてもらうぜ。
So we're helping out until the very end!
みんな！
Guys!
それだけじゃねえ。
And that's not all...
（ミナト）皆さん！
私のチャクラをつかんでください！
Everyone! Grab onto my chakra!
これだな！
This one?
よっしゃ！　みんな！
一斉に　せ～のでいくってばよ！
All right!
Everyone, we'll do it together
on my mark!
せ～の！！
Pull!
《俺が…》
Are you saying...
《この俺が…
後悔しているというのか》
That I...
I've got regrets...?!
お前は俺に　誰でもない
誰でもいたくないって言ったよな。
You once told me...
"I'm nobody..
"I don't want to be anybody..."
やめろ！　俺の中に入ってくるな！
Stop! Don't come into my thoughts!
でも　本当は俺と一緒で
火影になりたかったんだな。
But the truth is...
You wanted to become the Hokage,
just like me.
もしかしたら　俺は　アンタの後ろを
追っかけてた場合だって→
It could have even ended up where
I was chasing after your shadow...
あったかもしれねえんだな。
俺は　火影に憧れてるから。
since I've always wanted
to become the Hokage.
捨てきった過去と　甘い自分だ。
こんなものを…。
I threw away the past
and my naïve self!
So don't tell me I'm—
なら　なんで俺に見えんだよ。
Then why am I able to see this?
面して　自分隠したってダメだ。
You can't hide behind a mask.
アンタは　カカシ先生の友達で
父ちゃんの部下で→
You were Kakashi Sensei's friend...
my dad's subordinate...
an Uchiha like Sasuke...
サスケと同じ　うちはで
俺と同じ夢持つ先輩で→
and a shinobi of the Hidden Leaf
who had the same dream as me.
木ノ葉の忍だった。
何なんだいったい…。
What... What exactly...
do you want with me?!
お前は俺をどうしたい！？
アンタは　うちはオビトだってことだ。
To remind you that
you are Obito Uchiha.
言ったろ　ぜってぇ　その面
ひっぺがしてやるってよ！
I told you, didn't I?
I swore I'd tear that mask
right off your face!
kimi ni makechai sou na kurai
Almost to the point of losing to you
kimi ni nayamasare sou da
Feeling like you might torment me
kimi ni kikoecha dame dame dame da
Not wanting you to hear me no, no, no
kimi ni nagasare sou na kurai
Swept away by you
kimi ni shiteyarare sou da
Taken in by you
kimi o omoccha dame dame dame da
I shouldn't love you no, no, no
sugu wasurechatte dame da
It's not good that I'm so forgetful
uzukumattecha dame da
It's not good that I'm cowering
kizutsuitatte ana aitatte
Even if I'm wounded and pierced
massugu tatteirareruyou ni naritai
I want to be able to stand up straight
kimi ni makechai sou na kurai
Almost to the point of losing to you
kimi ni nayamasare sou da
Feeling like you might torment me
kimi ni kikoecha dame dame dame da
Not wanting you to hear me no, no, no
kimi ni nagasare sou na kurai
Swept away by you
kimi ni shiteyarare sou da
Taken in by you
kimi o omoccha dame dame dame da
I shouldn't love you no, no, no
Obito Uchiha?!
What meaning is there in that name...
in that existence now?
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Now that I've merged with the Ten Tails,
美空ひばりです。
I've transcended and
attained enlightenment.
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
In other words,
I am no longer human.
I am the one who will lead mankind
to its next stage.
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Obito Uchiha"
オープニングは　小林幸子さんと
美川憲一さんの→
I am the Second Sage of the Six Paths!
豪華なデュエットをお楽しみください。